战争要来临了
There is a war coming.
可怕的战争
A-a terrible war.
到时会一片混乱
There-there will be chaos.
街上血流成河
Rivers of blood in the streets.
我知道的
I know it!
我能预见到
I-I can see it coming.
是时候了
It's time.
总得有人接替他  那不如就让我来
Somebody has to take over; it might as well be me.
我叫詹姆斯・戈登
My name's James Gordon.
我是一名警探
I'm a detective.
我叫布鲁斯・韦恩
My-my name is Bruce Wayne.
我保证  我会找到凶手的
I promise, I will find the man who did this.
站住  不然我开枪了
Stop or I'll shoot!
他是被人栽赃
He was framed
掩盖真正的凶手
To cover up for the real killer.
我知道警局被你捏在手中
I know that you own the police department.
或许连市长也是
Probably the mayor, too.
没有法律  黑社会也无法生存
You can't have organized crime without law and order.
是你告密了
You snitched,
我的小企鹅
my little penguin.
求您了
Please.
法尔科内要你一枪崩了他
Falcone wants you to put a bullet in his head.
然后大家就都知道你会合作了
Then everybody knows you're with the program.
再也别回哥谭了
Don't ever come back to Gotham.
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制作
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
你在这儿呢
There you are.
我满屋子找你
Been all over the bloody house looking for you.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
没什么
Nothing.
你这孩子  根本不会撒谎
You, my old son, are a terrible liar.
你拿了什么
What have you got there?
来吧  给我看看
Come on. Show me.
上帝啊  你这个小蠢蛋
Oh, my God, you stupid little boy!
没事了  对不起
It's all right. I'm sorry.
一切都会好起来的
It's gonna be all right.
翻译：艾瑞卡   Reginamoon   夜影章鱼X   Silence   木浅薰
翻译：DustD   哥谭直属   charcie   爵士年代蓬蓬裙   草草
时间轴：宝宝   讷讷   最可爱的小胖子       后期 ：饿得慌
特效：宝宝          校对：草草           总监：草草
你们好  我是帕蒂
Hi! I'm Patti.
这位是道格
This is Doug.
我们是市长开展的
We're with the mayor's
"关心无家可归者"项目的工作人员
Homeless Outreach Project.
我们这儿有一些三明治和汤
We have some sandwiches and some soup.
还有曲奇饼  糖果
We got cookies, got candy.
谁喜欢巧克力
Who here likes chocolate?
你不饿吗  小猫
Ain't you hungry, Cat?
没错  吃吧  拿个三明治
Yeah, dig in. Take a sandwich.
-我正需要这个  -是啊  吃吧
- This is what I need. - Sure, go ahead.
人人都够分
Plenty for everyone.
来吧  拿两个吧
Yeah, sure. Take two.
干什么
Hey, lady.
该死的
Oh, fudge!
别担心  我这就去
Don't worry. I'll go.
慢点跑  牛仔
Slow down there, buckaroo.
我本来给你买了一杯  但不小心撒了
I got you one, but I dropped it.
谢了
Yeah, thanks.
其他人呢
Where is everybody?
不知道
I don't know.
你怎么看
What do you think?
我看这轮班已经很辛苦了
I think it's been a long shift.
我们再为这流浪汉挨三小时  然后就收工
We give this bum three hours, then we knock off.
他是个老兵
He was a vet.
我向他的贡献致敬
I salute his service.
但如今他只是个死掉的流浪汉
Now he's a dead bum.
经常有人射杀流浪汉
People are shooting bums all the time.
找凶手跟找牙仙一样希望渺茫
We might as well be looking for the tooth fairy.
-你们好啊  -你好  博
- Hey, guys. - Hey, Bo.
你之前怎么没到场
How come you weren't here?
你也早上好啊
Good morning to you, too.
-你去哪了  -我在街那边的一家餐厅
- Where were you? - I was at a restaurant down the street here,
客如归餐厅  有个吸毒流浪少年
Chez Vous. They had some homeless junkie kid,
昨晚从他们的前窗摔了进去
fell through their front window last night.
我一直忙那事儿呢
I been taking care of that.
这可能是一起凶杀案
This is a potential murder.
你是应急人员
You're first responder.
你本应保护犯罪现场的完整性
You're supposed to preserve the integrity of the crime scene.
他说的有道理
He's got a point.
那家餐厅每月付我50美金让我罩着他们
The restaurant that pays me $50 a month to look out for them.
你要我守着一个死掉的醉汉吗
So I wanna babysit a dead wino?
我可是要养家糊口的啊
I got a family.
他说的也有道理
He's got a point.
那流浪少年为什么冲进前窗
Why'd the kid jump through the window?
谁知道呢  他嗑嗨了
Who knows? He was high.
你问过他了吗
Did you ask him?
你为什么把我当坏人
Why am I the bad guy here?
我问那个流浪少年的情况
I'm asking about the kid
因为他可能和这个死者有关
because maybe he's related to the victim.
而且你也不是坏人
And you're not a bad guy--
你只是个坏警察而已
you're just a bad cop.
-你和谁说话呢  -冷静
- Who you talking to? - Hold on.
你知道吗  我已经...
You know, I already had...
来啊  来呀
Come on. Come on!
你想打一架吗  随时奉陪
You want it? Any day!
然后泽博和斯莫克就径直倒下了
And then Zeb and Smoke went right down,
然后那个怪人开枪杀了老兵
and that's when that wacky dude just shot Soldier.
然后我就意识到我得赶快逃走
That's when I realized I needed to get out of there.
我就跑啊跑
So I ran and I ran,
所以才跌进那家餐厅的地上
and that's how I ended up on the floor of that restaurant.
她用了大头针
She used a pin.
我发誓  超大的针
I swear. A big pin.
但听着  这不是第一次了
But, listen, this is not the first time.
这几周一直有流浪少年失踪
Street kids have been disappearing for weeks now.
已经有十多个人了  没人知道原因
By the dozen. No one knows why.
-这是我第一次听说  -当然了
- First we heard about it. - Why-why would you?
没人在乎我们
Nobody gives a crap about us.
瞧  这就能证明
I mean, look! That is proof!
那就是个疤  能证明什么  听着  迈奇
That's not proof. That's a scab. Now, listen, Macky,
我们都是成年人了  我们比你聪明
we're grown-ups. We're smarter than you.
随你怎么说吧
Man, whatever.
所以  你要告诉我真相
So you're gonna... you're gonna tell me the truth!
是你干的  对不对
It was you, wasn't it?
是你杀了那个可怜的老人
It was you that killed that poor old man.
就是你  你得跟我实话实说
It was you. Now, you're gonna tell me the truth,
不然我对天发誓  我打也要把真相打出来
or I swear to God, I'm gonna beat it out of you!
那个老人是退伍军人啊
That old man was a war veteran!
小猫当时也在
Listen, Cat was there.
小猫全都看到了  去问她
Cat saw the whole thing. Ask Cat.
-去问小猫  -别激动  迈奇
- Ask Cat! - Relax, Macky, relax.
没人会打你的  小猫是谁
No one's gonna beat you. Who's Cat?
什么叫没人会打他
What do you mean, no one's gonna beat him?
我不是刚说要打他吗  就刚才
Isn't that what I just said I was gonna do right now, just now?
-我要打他  -过来
- I was gonna beat him? - Come here!
过来  过来
Come here. Come here.
他才16岁
He is 16.
一米八的个头又那么壮  打一拳没事的
Yeah, and six-foot, 220. He can take a punch.
我不会真打他的  只是想吓吓他
Look, I wasn't gonna beat him. I just wanted to scare him.
但我要是真想打他  我也能打
But if I did want to beat him, I could.
-那是我的特权  -这不合法
- It would be my prerogative. - It's illegal.
不合...
Ill...
你现在又这么义正言辞了
How now so righteous?
你不是才把一个人扔进河里吗
Not long since you put a man in the river.
说大点声行吗
You want to say that a little louder?
有人没听到
Not everybody heard.
自那以后  你就一直给我找麻烦
Ever since then, you've been a royal pain in the ass.
你以为我或这里的任何人
You think I or anybody around here
会在意一个死掉的告密者
gives a crap about a dead snitch
或者你的良心不安吗
or your guilty conscience?
-我们有自己要担心的  -良心不安
- We got our own problems. - Guilty conscience,
随你怎么说  我要做正确的事
call it what you want. I'm gonna do what's right.
你真有点惹火我了
You're beginning to irritate me.
把你的手拿开
Get your hands off me.
别踩我鞋  混蛋
Watch the shoes, clown.
下班了
Shift's over.
来吧
Come on.
上来吧  不闹了
Come on. Seriously.
真的很感谢你们
Thank you so much, guys, truly.
我很感激  我等了好久了
I'm very grateful. I've been waiting for hours.
可不是  你看起来像从坟地里爬出来的
No kidding. Look like you crawled out of a cemetery.
闻着也像  把后面的窗户打开
Smells like it, too. Open a window back there.
-好了  -嗯
- There you go. - Yeah.
谢谢你
Yes, thank you.
不好意思  现在有点衣冠不整
Forgive me, I am somewhat disheveled.
只是暂时受挫  我保证
A temporary setback, I assure you.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
到底发生什么事了
What the hell happened to you anyhow?
是我的错
It was my own fault.
愚蠢的自大蒙蔽了我
Foolish arrogance led me astray.
但我吸取了教训
But I learned my lessons.
我会重新站起来  比以前更强更聪明
I'll be back, stronger and smarter than ever.
祝你好运了  老兄
Good luck with that, bro.
我坐在漂亮的车里
Here I am riding around in a lovely truck,
跟我的新朋友一起喝冰啤兜风
sharing an ice-cold beer with my new friends.
我已经转运了  不是吗
My luck's already turned, right?
老兄  有人跟你说过
Dude, anyone ever tell you,
你走起路来像只企鹅吗
when you walk, you look just like a penguin?
没有
No.
没人跟我说过
Nobody's ever told me that.
哥谭
第一季第二集
他说他有权拦着我不让我揍流浪汉
He's saying he has a right to stop me from beating on a mope.
我当然有权
Damn right I do.
让我怎么跟这种人合作
How am I supposed to work with this?
听着  吉姆  我又不能叫你去犯法
Look it, Jim, it's not like I can order you to break the law,
但这里是哥谭
but this is Gotham.
你不妥协  就活不下去
You don't bend, you'll get broke.
我明白
I understand.
我以为你是会合作的
I thought you were with the program.
-他是  -那继续说案子的事吧
- He is. - Well, let's get back to work.
-查得怎样了  -如果那小子说得是真的
- Where are you at? - Well, if the boy we have is telling the truth,
那就是有一个绑架团伙
there's a couple of kidnappers out there
在大肆绑架无家可归的少年
abducting homeless children in numbers.
他们开着市长"关心无家可归者"项目的卡车
They lured them close with a food truck
把这些孩子吸引过来  然后下手
from the mayor's Homeless Outreach Project.
手法是用一根大针头刺他们来下药
And they drugged them with a jab from a big pin.
怎么会有人想绑架一大堆邋里邋遢的流浪孤儿
Wh-Why would anyone want to abduct scaggly-ass orphans in bulk?
哪有市场需求啊
I mean, where's the market?
他们上街流浪  正是因为他们没人管没人要
They're out on the street because no one wants them anyway.
要是说有人绑架漂亮妹子
If they said they were snatching cute girls,
这我信
I'd believe 'em.
但谁会想要迈奇这种没用的猪头
But what would anyone want with a lard-ass like Macky?
怎么了  爱德
What is it, Ed?
猜猜我发现了什么
Guess what I found.
我给他验了血  检测出了大量的ATP
I did a blood test on him, and he had high levels of ATP.
什么是ATP呀
What's ATP?
是一种速效迷药
It's a fast-acting knockout drug.
阿卡姆疯人院以前用过这药
They used to use it at the old Arkham Asylum
来药倒闹得凶的病人
to bring down troublesome patients.
很难搞到
It's hard to get.
也没什么消遣作用
No recreational use.
好吧  是有点意思
Okay. That's interesting.
还有别的吗
Anything else?
多谢了  爱德
Thank you, Ed.
谢谢你了  爱德
去查吧
Get to work.
别走漏消息
And keep this quiet.
不能让媒体知道  一个字都不行
No press. Not a word.
难道不该把情况告诉公众吗
Shouldn't we tell the public what's going on?
-警告他们一下  -本局有政策
- Warn them? - Department policy.
这种事我们不声张  以免引起恐慌
We don't advertise this kind of stuff. Causes panic.
头条肯定会写"哥谭儿童遭到绑架"
The headlines will read "Gotham's Kids Snatched."
-这确有其事  -不让媒体知道  这是命令
- Which would be true. - No press. That's an order.
追查ATP这种药的线索
Follow up on the drug, the ATP
还有跟阿卡姆的联系
and the Arkham connection.
阿卡姆都关了十多年了
Arkham's been closed for, like, ten years.
没错  15年了
Yeah, 15.
供药商可能还没关门
Drug suppliers might still be in business.
这事发生在菲什・穆尼的地盘上
This happened on Fish Mooney's turf.
要不要先问问我们去查安不安全
Do you want to see if it's safe for us to go back there,
看看她是不是还在生我们的气
or is, uh, she still mad at us?
问得好
That's a good question.
精彩
Bravo!
太精彩了
法尔科内阁下
Don Falcone.
实在是意外之喜  快请坐
What a wonderful surprise. Welcome.
谢谢  亲爱的
Thank you, my dear.
我们能聊聊吗
Can we... talk?
-当然  我先清场  -不必
- Of course. Give me a moment to clear the place. - No, no.
不必搅了大家的兴致
No need to spoil the fun.
人之将死  其言也善
Men who are about to die are very honest.
善言值得一听
It pays to listen to them.
好个祝酒词
That's some toast.
你手下科波特死前  我和他谈过
I spoke with your man Cobblepot before he died.
真是个奇怪的小子  但挺聪明
Odd little fellow. Perceptive.
他和我说韦恩夫妇的死
He told me the death of the Waynes
会给我们家族和哥谭带来麻烦
would bring troubled times for our family and Gotham.
那小子知道什么
What did he know?
我们的生意依旧蒸蒸日上
Business is good as ever.
不  他说得对
No, he was right.
韦恩夫妇和法尔科内家族是同一栋房子的支柱
The Waynes and the Falcones were the pillars of the same house.
我们彼此理解
We understood each other.
现在他们死了  一切都失去了平衡
Now that they're gone, everything is out of balance,
韦恩帝国也会摇摆不定
and the Wayne Empire is in flux.
谁知道最终谁将大权在握呢
Who knows who will end up in control?
马罗尼家族察觉局势不稳
The Maroni family senses weakness.
就会开始有所行动
They'll start making moves,
这座城市的所有罪犯也都会开始有所行动
and every criminal in the city will start making moves.
可别为马罗尼担心
Please don't lose any sleep over Maroni.
他居于第二位  不是没有原因的
He's number two for a reason.
我从不担心我的敌人
I never lose sleep over my enemies.
倒是我的朋友令我担忧
It's my friends that keep me awake.
科波特告诉我你跟他说
Cobblepot told me you say
我年老不中用了  该铲除我了
I'm old and soft and ready to be taken out,
你就是该取代我的人
and you're the one to take me.
法尔科内阁下  我是绝对
Don Falcone, I would never,
不会这么说的
ever say that.
我对您只有深深的爱意及敬意
I only have deep love and respect for you.
对我而言  您就像父亲
You have been like a father to me.
我很高兴听你这么说
I'm so... happy to hear that.
忘记刚才所说的一切吧
Let's forget all about it, then.
不过是将死之人的胡言乱语
The babbling of a condemned man.
公事说完了
Enough business.
你最近怎么样  亲爱的
How have you been, my dear?
但愿你一切都好
Thriving, I hope.
是的  很好  很好
Yes. Good. I'm good.
哪一个是你的情人
Which of these is your lover?
拜托  我的心早被爱情什么的伤透了
Please. My heart has been broken far too many times for that nonsense.
我听说你有个情人
I heard you had a lover.
如果你是指我拿来活动身子的男人...
Well, if you're referring to the boy that I keep around for exercise-
他可绝不是我的情人
my lover he is not.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫拉兹罗  先生
Lazlo, sir.
拉兹罗  对她好点
Lazlo, be good to this woman.
她可是我的至宝
She's very precious to me.
如果你伤了她的心
If you break her heart,
也就是伤我的心
you break my heart.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
把你的手给我
Give me your hand.
谢谢你的坦诚  这对我来说很重要
Thank you for being honest. It means a lot to me.
这显示了你的智慧
It shows wisdom
和谦虚
and humility.
出去
Out!
全部给我滚出去
Everyone out!
我儿子这辈子从没离开我这么久过
Never, never in his life my son is away this long.
夜店是他的事业
Nightclubs is his business.
总工作到很晚
Such hours.
但他总是会回家  回到母亲身边
But always, he comes home to his mother.
他的衣服都在这儿
His clothes are here.
我儿子绝对不会落下他的衣服的
My son would never leave his clothes.
他是那么讲究
Oh, so elegant, he is.
我拿给你们看
Yes, I-I show you.
见鬼
Damn.
穆尼肯定是联手警局的人把他给杀了
Mooney and the cops must have had him killed.
那就是告密的小子被干掉了
Looks like the snitches get bumped.
人生就这么残酷
That's life.
我不会让他们逍遥法外的
They're not going to get away with it,
没这么容易
not as easy as they think.
你总是太容易动感情  你知道吗
You take things too personally, you know what?
当然  他是个好线人
Yeah, I do. That was a good snitch.
-你们说什么呢...  -没什么
- What are we...? - Nothing.
科波特太太
Uh, Mrs. Cobblepot...
卡佩普特
Kapelput.
卡佩普特太太  您知道有谁会想要伤害您儿子吗
Mrs. Kapelput, do you know anyone who might want to do your son harm?
伤害
Harm?
没有  我会察觉到的
No. I-I would feel it.
母亲能察觉到这种事
A mother feels these things.
是个女人
It's a woman.
是个浓妆艳抹的婊子拴住了他
Some painted slut has him in her clutch.
你觉得  是因为女人
A woman... you think?
我敢肯定
I am sure.
他是那么帅
So handsome he is.
还很天真
And so naive.
你们是谁来着
Who are you again?
重案组的警探  女士
Uh, detectives with Major Crimes Unit, ma'am.
哥谭市警局
Oh, GCPD.
差不多
Like that.
但清廉一些
But honest.
老大  别生我气
Boss, don't get mad at me,
不过我懂那表情
but I know that look.
现在对法尔科内动手还太早
Now is too early to make a move on Falcone.
我知道
I know.
时候未到
Not yet.
我需要更多的钱  人力  还有领土
I need more money, more men, more territory,
我知道
I know.
我会假装忠诚  等待时机
I'll play this thing loyal and bide my time.
但我向我母亲神圣的坟墓起誓  布奇
But I swear, Butch, on my sainted mother's grave,
不久之后
some day soon,
我就会用我的双手和利齿  杀了那个老头子
I am going to kill that old man with my bare hands and my teeth.
我会为您提鞋的
I'll be holding your shoes.
我真希望那个小企鹅还活着
I just wish that Penguin was still alive.
那小混蛋受得折磨真是远远不够
I didn't make that little punk suffer near badly enough.
打扰了  先生
Excuse me, sir?
我注意了您拖车上的标志
I couldn't help but notice the sign on your trailer.
出租
还可以租吗
Is it still for rent?
一百块一周  不算太好  不过...
100 bucks a week. It ain't much, but...
-我租了  -你不先看看吗
- I'll take it. - You don't want to look at it first?
不了  我不挑剔
No, I'm not fussy.
归你了
It's all yours.
钥匙呢
The key?
车不错啊  装了汽缸发动机吗
Hey, sweet truck. You got that big hemi in there?
是啊  是的
Yes. Yup.
是有个汽缸发动机
That big hemi's in there.
什么的
Somewhere.
先生  钥匙呢
Uh, sir, the key?
在门上呢
It's in the door.
好的
Okay.
好啊  二位
What's up, players?
你们有烟吗
You got any smokes?
没有
No.
我们在哪
Where are we?
我哪知道
Damn if I know.
我觉得我们死定了
I think we're dead.
哈维
Harvey.
吉姆  真太好了
Jim. How marvelous.
你还在生我们气呢
You still mad at us?
没有  得了
No. Please.
我挺喜欢你的  而你...
I'm quite fond of you, and...
让我感兴趣
you intrigue me.
我一下令杀了你们  我就知道我会后悔
I knew I'd regret killing you as soon as I gave the word.
但你了解我的  我火气大
But you know me. I'm feisty.
你了不了解
What do you know about
在你地盘上绑架流浪少年的一男一女
a man and a woman abducting street kids on your turf?
你不玩前戏是吧
No foreplay with you, hmm?
猜到了  不过你也是自己人了
Figures, but you got with the program.
你自己亲手杀了小企鹅
Killed Penguin your own bad self.
我真没想到
I was surprised.
你那么正直呢
Straight arrow like you.
-看来你看错了我  -看来是的
- I guess you misjudged me. - I guess I did.
你也是个罪人  跟我们其他人一样
You're just a little sinner like the rest of us.
我都有点为此难过呢
I'm almost kind of sad about that.
我们在找一男一女
We're looking for a man and a woman,
中年
middle-aged,
白人
white,
他们对不满16岁的孩子下手
targeting children under 16.
作案工具是毒针  相信吗
They use a poisoned pin, if you can believe it.
要是以前只有漂亮姑娘才有市场
Used to be there was only a market for nice-looking girls.
我也是这么说的
That's what I said.
但现在有个国外的新买家
But now there's a new buyer overseas
他们愿接受所有年轻健康的人
that will take anyone young and healthy.
国外哪里  谁是"他们"
Overseas where? Who's "they"?
没人知道
Nobody knows.
他们想做什么
What do they want 'em for?
没人知道
Nobody knows.
也没人想知道
And no one cares to know.
来啦  木须肉
Ta-da! Moo shu.
抱歉  继续说
Sorry. Go on.
他们用长针毒晕他们
They drug them with a big pin?
好恐怖
That is so creepy.
不说了  你不会想听的  太让人郁闷了
No, you don't want to hear this stuff. It's depressing.
他们拿那些孩子做什么
What do they use them for? The children?
没人知道
Nobody seems to know.
而且不能向媒体透露  不利于形象
And we can't say a damn thing to the press. Bad PR.
真难以相信警局这么腐败
I can't believe the system is so corrupt.
-你都想不到  -这话什么意思
- You have no idea. - What do you mean?
没有  就是说说啦
No. You know, figure of speech, I guess.
你有没有事瞒着我
Did something happen that you're not telling me about?
这几周
These last couple of weeks...
你很不对劲  忧心忡忡的
You've been different, troubled.
没有
No.
可能最近睡眠不好
Been having trouble sleeping, I guess.
报社一定常常接到匿名线报
The newspapers must get anonymous tips all the time.
那是
Oh, sure, yeah.
什么  我自己泄密吗
You mean, call it in myself?
不行  我不能那么做
No, I can't do that.
是《哥谭公报》新闻编辑部吗
Gotham Gazette. The newsroom.
别这样
Wait. No.
你好  是这样  我不能说太久
Hi. Listen, I can't talk long.
最近有人在绑架街上的流浪儿
Somebody is abducting homeless children off the streets,
警方试图对此保密
and the cops are trying to keep it quiet.
去找哥谭市警局的莎拉・艾森警监聊聊
Go talk to Captain Sarah Essen of the GCPD.
她那儿有个被拘留的孩子能跟你讲清楚
She has got a kid in custody who can tell you the whole story.
-挂电话  -我得挂了
- End the call. - I got to go.
听我说  芭芭拉
Listen to me, Barbara.
我跟你说的事  是咱俩之间的秘密
When I tell you stuff, that's just between us.
你以后不能再这样做了
You can't do that, what you just did.
但这才是正确的做法
But it was the right thing to do.
-这不是重点  -那重点是什么
- That's not the point. - Well, what is the point?
你说得对  这是正确的做法
You're right. It was the right thing to do.
但别再这么做了  行吗
Don't do it again, okay?
是  长官
Yes, boss.
哥谭公报
儿童遭绑架
"哥谭每况愈下"
"Gotham spirals ever downward."
"詹姆斯市长受到指责"
"Mayor James under attack."
"保证马上采取行动"
"Vows swift action."
"矛头指向警局的迟钝反应"  等等
"Points finger at police department's sluggish response." Et cetera.
报纸而已
It's just ink.
是你泄的密吗
Did you give them this?
我
Me?
你也不是没做过
You've done it before.
给自己下绊子  绝不可能
On my own case? Never.
那可太傻了
Be a very stupid thing to do.
吉姆
Jim?
不是我说的
I didn't call it in.
我发誓
I swear.
又一桩谜案啊
Another mystery.
我们找到了条模糊线索  您想听吗  长官
We have a thin lead on the case, if you'd like to hear it, ma'am.
哥谭只有三家公司存储这种迷药
There's only three companies in Gotham that stock this ATP stuff,
而且需要特殊许可证才能购买
and you need a special license to buy it.
很可能是其中一家在和他们同流合污
Chances are, one of the three's crooked.
我们打算给三家都施加点压力
We're looking to lean hard on all three,
当作是犯了事对待  看谁会露马脚
like they are crooked, see which one pops.
你装的真像
That was sneaky good.
差点就被你骗过去了
Almost couldn't tell you were lying.
我说的是真话
I wasn't lying.
早上好  贝克法官
Good morning, Judge Baker.
谢谢  先生  是的  三家都要
Thank you, sir. Yes, all three.
韦尔茨公司
Welzyne,
德拉古工业和奎伦制药
Dracotech and Quillan Pharma.
你们把我害惨了
You guys have screwed me.
我虽觉得不妥
Against my better judgment,
但还是卖给你们那些药
I sell you the juice,
还让你们借用我的仓库
I let you guys use my storage space
因为你们说不会有事
because, "No problem," you said.
现在瞧瞧
And now look.
儿童遭绑架
麻烦
Heat.
大麻烦
White-hot heat.
没事的  朋友
No problems, my friend.
我们就是来转移货物的
We're here to take the merch away.
你不会受牵连的
You'll be clean as a whistle.
货物
Merch?
他们可是孩子
They're children, damn it.
是活生生的人
They're human beings.
我不是10分钟前就让你去看看他们了吗
Didn't I tell you to check on them ten minutes ago?
再给我五千
I want another five large.
但我们已经谈好价格了
But we had a deal already.
我得做正确的事啊
I got to stand up for what is right here.
讲点理  先生  我们没这么多现金
Be fair, sir. We don't have that kind of cash on hand.
那是你的问题  我可以等
That's your problem. I can wait.
你不是担心会招来麻烦吗
I thought you was worried about the heat.
如果麻烦真的来了
Well, if heat arrives in the meantime,
我也可以很迅速地消灭证据
I can get rid of the evidence very quickly.
我们必须把货送到
We have an obligation to deliver.
人偶师绝不会容许失败
The Dollmaker doesn't tolerate failure.
我们需要那些孩子
We need those children.
那也是你们的问题
Well, that's also your problem.
不  这太过分了
No. Hey, hey, this is totally inappropriate.
我们是在谈生意哎
I mean, we were having a business discussion here.
但你太不讲理了
You weren't being fair.
倒霉  是警察
Oh, gosh. Cops.
你是没给公报打电话  但你女朋友打了  对吧
You didn't call the Gazette, but did your girl call the Gazette?
药房
对
Yeah.
-我就知道  -我也不知道她会打啊
- I knew it. - I didn't know she was gonna call 'em.
说真的  你得好好管管你的女人了
Seriously, you got to learn to control your woman.
我倒挺喜欢她这样呢
I kind of like her the way she is.
这些上流社会的任性小妞
No, these high-class temperamental broads --
她们需要好好管教  相信我吧
they need firm handling. Trust me.
-相信你对女人的判断  -一点没错
- Trust you? On women? - Damn right.
我泡过各种女人  从家庭主妇到电影明星
All varieties. From hausfraus to movie stars.
我都喜欢  你呢  我猜猜看
I love 'em all. Now, you? Let me guess.
高中女友  在海外时嫖过
High school sweetheart. Then a bunch of hos overseas
但你并不开心
only made you sad,
然后就遇到了芭芭拉
and then there's Barbara.
差不多
Pretty much.
伙计  你就是只骑着赛马的猴子
You, my friend, are a monkey riding a racehorse.
晚上好  有什么需要帮助的
Good evening. May I help you?
戈登和布洛克警探  我们需要
Detectives Gordon and Bullock. We need to speak
-和这里管事的人谈谈  -好的
- to whoever's in charge here, ma'am. - Of course.
奎伦先生  有警探找你
Mr. Quillan, detectives are here to see you.
二位警探  什么事啊
Detectives. Hey, what's up?
希望没什么大事
Nothing serious, I hope.
别废话  我们有对这里的搜查证
Cut the crap. We have a warrant to search the premises.
我们知道你干了什么
We know what you're doing.
那一定都是些无聊的事
Well, then, you know some boring stuff, then.
你们什么意思啊
I mean, what are you talking about?
你在给绑架孩子的人提供ATP
You're peddling ATP to those kid snatchers.
我的天哪  没有啊
Oh, my gosh, no. I-I mean,
我们以前是囤有ATP
we used to stock ATP,
但阿卡姆疯人院关了之后就没有了
but not since the Arkham Asylum closed.
我听说韦恩基金会
Uh, uh... I heard that the Wayne Foundation
本打算重开精神病院
is planning on reopening the old place again.
不过现在韦恩夫妇死了
But now that the Waynes are dead,
一切都是未知数了吧
I guess everything's up in the air.
什么世道啊  是吧
What a world, eh?
没人是安全的
Nobody's safe.
-吉姆  -追  追
- Jim! - Go, go!
你刚才死哪去了
Where the hell were you?
快去干掉他们
Get rid of 'em now.
把房间洗干净
And hose down the room.
泽博
Zeb.
不许动
Freeze.
我谨代表哥谭市民
On behalf of all the citizens of Gotham,
衷心地感谢二位勇敢的警探
I want to thank you brave gentlemen from the bottom of my heart,
我向你们这群孩子保证
and I want to promise you kids--
我们会照顾好你们
we will take care of you
就像对待自己家人一样
as if you were our own children.
但问题是
But here's the thing.
伤害这些孩子的人仍逍遥法外
The people who victimized these kids are still out there.
数以百计的脆弱的孩子
And hundreds of vulnerable youngsters
仍落魄街头
are still living rough on our streets.
孤苦伶仃  无人保护
Alone, unprotected,
我们面对现实吧  这才是真正的罪孽
and let's face it, that's the real crime here.
我们要怎么保护这些孩子
So what are we going to do to help these kids?
昨天  我已联络青少年保护机构和哥谭市警局
Yesterday I made a phone call to Juvenile Services and the GCPD
启动了一项人道的严爱计划
to initiate a humane but tough-love program
将流落街头的孩子
to get these kids off the streets
送入青少年保护机构的温暖怀抱中
and into the loving arms of Juvenile Services.
挺顺利的啊
I think that went very well.
是啊
I think so.
来上一杯吗  阁下
A small toast, Your Honor?
你真了解我
You read my mind.
市长先生
Mr. Mayor.
你把抓起来的孩子送到哪里去了
Uh, where are you sending all the children that get rounded up?
可爱健康的送去寄养家庭
Foster homes for the cute, undamaged ones.
其余的送去州北
Upstate for the rest.
州北
Upstate?
阿尔皮纳少管所
The Alpena Youth Corrections Facility.
一家不错的机构
A fine institute.
换句话说就是监狱
Prison, in other words.
请原谅  阁下
Forgive me, your Honor.
戈登警探是我们这儿的热血青年
Detective Gordon's our house firebrand.
不不  没关系
No, no, no, th-that's okay.
吉姆  我可以叫你吉姆吗
Jim... May I call you Jim?
这座城市一半的轻罪
Half the petty crime in the city
都是流浪少年干的
is homeless kids.
他们需要管教
They need structure.
需要有人照顾
People who care for them.
这是为了哥谭的大局和这些孩子着想啊  懂吗
For the greater good of Gotham and for the children. You see?
我只知道你利用儿童绑架犯作幌子
I see you're using the child snatchers as a pretext
不经审理就将这些孩子关起来
to lock up children without a trial.
谢谢你  朋友
Thank you, my friend.
很有价值的想法
Valuable input.
醍醐灌顶啊
Most refreshing.
干杯
L'chaim.
戈登
Yo, Gordon.
有人在楼上等你
Man's been waiting for you upstairs.
潘尼沃斯先生
Mr. Pennyworth.
叫我阿尔弗雷德就好
Alfred, please.
真是够乱的
It's bedlam, isn't it?
你的工作很不易啊
Rough job you got.
这是世上最好的工作了
Best job in the world.
不知道你明天方不方便来我们家一趟
I wonder if it might be convenient for you to visit us tomorrow.
方便
Of course.
怎么了  出什么事了吗
Why? Is something wrong?
我也说不好
I don't know.
我以前从没带过孩子
Never had a child before.
我也没有
Nor me.
那孩子尊敬你
The boy respects you.
5点多吧  行吗
Teatime, shall we say?
好啊
Teatime.
姓名
Name.
女士  你们搞错了
Ma'am, there's been a mistake.
我不该去州北的
I'm not meant to go upstate.
我得和詹姆斯・戈登谈谈  他是个警探
I need to talk to James Gordon. He's a cop.
等你到了地方  就可以用电话了  姓名
You'll be allowed a phone call when you get upstate. Name.
我必须现在就跟他谈
I need to talk to him now.
-他会感谢你的  -不可能  姓名
- He'll thank you for it. - Not happening. Name.
你能把我怎样  猪头
Bite me, Pigarina.
无名女
Jane Doe.
别紧张  小子
Relax, kid.
少管所也没那么糟
Juvie's not so bad.
第一周  千万千万
First week, whatever you do,
别和那些看着友善的人交朋友
don't make friends with anyone that's friendly.
要是跟人打起来了  直击对手的眼睛
When you get into a fight, go for their eyes.
孩子们  你们好吗
Hiya, kids. How you doing?
准备好去大冒险了吗
Are you ready to go on a big adventure?
坐下  小姑娘
Sit down, young lady.
我说了  坐下
I said sit down.
马上
Like now.
好了
Okay.
谁再敢调皮站起来
Next naughty child to stand up
我就给他这儿来一下
gets a black mark right here.
少了一个  或两三个  我还能解释
One or two or three-- I could explain that.
但少了一车
But a busload--
整整一车的小杂种
a whole busload of the little bastards--
你要我怎么解释
what am I supposed to say?
"不小心哦"  求你告诉我  不是他们干的
Oops? Just tell me it wasn't them, I'm begging you.
千万别是那些绑架犯干的
Just tell me it wasn't the snatchers.
开车的是个男人  警卫是女的
Bus driver was a man, guard was a woman.
可能是他们
It could be them.
你要害死我了  你要害死我了
You're killing me. You're killing me.
我们在查了  阁下
We're working it, Your Honor.
我知道的都告诉你们了  我都说了
Look, I told you everything I know. I told you.
看到旁边这人了吗
Now, you see that man there?
他不喜欢我动手打人
He doesn't like it when I beat people,
但对你他完全没意见  为什么呢
but for you, he's got no objection. Why is that?
我算得清
Math.
30个孩子抵得上你这人渣的狗命
The lives of 30 children versus one scumbag.
所以就算我拿你当鼓打
So I can beat you like a bongo drum
这位圣人也不会说一句
and Saint Jim here won't intervene.
给我们点线索
Give us something.
好吧
Okay, okay, look...
那辆卡车
The truck.
就是他们来接最后一批孩子时开的那辆
You know, when they came to pick up the last bunch of kids.
车侧面有张图片
On the side of it, there was a-a picture.
像个商标那种
Like a logo.
我之前没说
I-I didn't want to say before
是因为会让人往坏处想
because it would give a bad impression.
因为也未必就是...
See, it doesn't reflect, really, what, you know...
-到底是什么  -一张蓝盘子和一把银叉子
- What was it? - It has a... a blue plate and a silver fork.
-盘子和叉子  -对  就是那种...
- A plate and a fork? - Yeah, you know, like, with the...
-你是说餐饮公司那种的吗  -嗯
- Like a catering company? Like food? - Well, yeah, like that,
就是那样  不过那也未必就是...
I mean, you know, but, I mean, that doesn't mean... You know.
未必是什么
Doesn't mean what?
我不知道他们要拿那些孩子怎么样
Look, I don't know what they do to them. Aah!
好了  画出那个商标  解开手铐
All right, draw the logo. Uncuff him.
好嘞  孩子们
There you go, kids.
别担心  没事的
Don't worry. Everything's gonna be all right.
就这样  快点走
That's right. That's right. Come on.
-快走  -快点
- Come on, come on, come on, come on. - Come on!
快走
Go.
真有意思  我没数错的话
Funny thing. By my count,
按他们给我们的名单  还少一个人
according to the sheet they gave us, we're one short.
我数着也是  车上可能还有一个
Me, too. Maybe there's one on the bus.
没有  真是怪了
Nope. Weird.
那一定是谁数错了
Must be a miscount someplace.
算了  这些孩子足够了
Never mind. We got more than enough.
我们做得真好
We did good.
是啊
Indeed we did.
人偶师一定会满意的
The Dollmaker will be so pleased with us.
好  谢谢
All right, thanks.
没查到  你呢
Nothing. You?
看来哥谭没有哪家公司
Apparently, there are no companies
有用盘子和叉子做商标的卡车
in Gotham with trucks with a plate and a fork as their logo.
拿孩子当食物卖吗
Selling children for food?
这种事有可能吗
Is such a thing even possible?
我们安排了警员在所有桥梁和隧道
We've got officers searching all the trucks
排查每一辆卡车
on every bridge and tunnel.
但他们已经抢先了3小时
But they had a three-hour window.
我们只能祈祷他们还留在市里
We can only pray they stayed in the city.
否则  到了晚上  他们早逃到天涯海角了
If not, they could be any place on Earth by nightfall.
这些人渣  到底跑哪去了
Scum-sucking toads. Where are they?!
不是蓝盘子
It's not a blue plate.
也不是叉子  是三叉戟
It's not a fork, either. It's a trident.
三叉戟国际运输
把他们装上船的时候
When you stow this on the ship,
一定留出开门的地方
make sure there's plenty of room for the doors to open.
船员会...
The ship's crew has...
闭嘴
Quiet in there!
行了
Hush.
别吵吵
我的眼睛  她挠我
My eyes! She scratched me!
跟我来吧
Come on, follow me.
我看看
Let me look.
没事的  就是抓伤
It's nothing. It's a scratch.
我们带你去找医生  你很快就会没事了
We'll get you to the doctor, you'll be right as rain in no time.
真的
You sure?
-什么声音  -等等
- What was that? - Hang on.
哎呀
Well...
你真是个淘气的小姑娘
You are a very naughty little girl.
你叫什么
What's your name?
关你什么事
Why is that your business?
吉姆
Jim!
那些孩子在哪
Where are the kids?
在哪
Where are they?!
他失眠
He's not been sleeping.
即使睡着了也会做恶梦
And when he does, he has these nightmares.
现在又开始自残
Now he's hurting himself.
烧自己
Burning himself.
割伤自己
He's cutting.
有给他找人看看吗
Is he getting professional help?
心理医生吗
Oh, you mean a psychiatrist?
他不肯
No, no, he won't have 'em.
不见心理医生
No psychiatrists.
这是原则
That's a rule.
原则不是你定的吗
You make the rules, don't you?
你是他的监护人
You're his guardian.
布鲁斯的父亲曾严格指示过
Bruce's father gave me very firm orders
如果他们夫妻俩死了要怎么做
was him and his missus to die.
我会按他父亲的意愿把孩子带大
Now, I will raise the boy the way his father told me to raise him.
那是怎么做
Which is how?
相信他会选择好自己的人生路
Trust him to choose his own course.
毕竟  他是韦恩家的人
He's, after all, a Wayne.
听上去只会造成灾难
Sounds like a recipe for disaster.
你要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
他想要你好好劝劝我
He wants you to talk some sense into me.
我不是叫你别那么
Haven't I told you to stop creeping up
偷偷摸摸的吗  太没礼貌了
on people like that before? It's bloody rude!
好吧  布鲁斯
All right, then, Bruce.
跟我谈谈吧
Talk to me.
我没事
I'm perfectly fine.
阿尔弗雷德就是瞎担心
Alfred's a worrywart.
你怎么你的手了
What did you do to your hand?
烧伤了
I burned it.
听我说  布鲁斯
Listen to me, Bruce.
你经历了一件可怕的事
You've been through a terrible experience.
跟人谈谈可能对你有好处
Talking to someone can be very helpful.
你在战时一定也见过很多可怕的事
You must have seen terrible things in the war.
那你跟人谈你看到的事对你有好处吗
Does it... does it help you to talk about what you saw?
是的  有一点吧
Yes. A little.
你不太擅长撒谎
You're not a very good liar.
布鲁斯  你在自残
Bruce, you're hurting yourself.
我在考验自己
I'm testing myself.
这不一样  但是多谢你关心了
Different, but I appreciate your concern.
我一直在报纸上关注你的动向
I've been following your adventures in the newspapers.
我很为那些可怜的孩子难过
I feel very sorry for all those poor children.
我也是
Me, too.
我给你些钱  你去拿给他们
I'll give you some money to give to them.
恐怕事情不是那么办的  布鲁斯
I'm afraid it doesn't work that way, Bruce.
那要怎么办
What way does it work?
那些孩子需要有人照顾
Those children need someone who cares for them,
就像有人在照顾你
like you have right here.
这是钱买不到的
Money won't buy that.
我肯定能做点什么
There must be something I can do.
衣服呢
What about clothes?
他们看上去衣衫褴褛的
They all looked awfully ragged.
是啊
They did, didn't they?
经历了这么多
After all this?
-你们还要送我们去州北  -塞琳娜
- You're sending us upstate? - Selina...
是小猫
Cat.
小猫  即使你没有一堆通缉令  你也才13
Cat, even if you didn't have outstanding warrants, you're 13.
没有父母和监护人
No parents or guardians.
不是的  我有个妈妈
That's not true. I have a mom.
-这里写着她死了  -不是的
- Says here she's deceased. - That's not true.
她还活着  只是不知所踪
She's alive... someplace.
就算如此
Be that as it may,
我们不能让你继续流落街头
we're not allowed to put you back on the street.
这是为了你好
It's for your own well-being.
你去过州北吗
Have you been there? Upstate?
-是的  -那你就该知道
- Yes. - Then you know.
你知道那里的情况
You know.
去找詹姆斯・戈登警探
Go get Detective James Gordon.
他在这儿工作
He works here.
小猫
Cat...
警察都是大忙人
the police are very busy people.
去找他
Go get him...
否则
or...
我就说你摸我
I'll say you touched me.
什么
Excuse me?
詹姆斯・戈登
James Gordon.
再过3秒钟  我就大喊
I'm gonna scream in about three seconds.
哥谭市
韦恩  布洛克  帮凶戈登  哭鼻子布鲁斯  市政府渣滓
猪猡  笨蛋  法尔科内
贱人
喂
Hello.
是我
Yes, this is he.
您儿子就在我面前呢
Well... I'm looking at your son right now, and...
他情况不太好
he doesn't look good.
女士  我保证  您儿子不是在骗您
Madam, I assure you, your son is not trying to trick you.
他会死得很惨的  除非...
Oh, he will die a horrible death unless he...
这是真的  不是他开玩笑
No, no. No, really truly, he isn't joking.
我也没开玩笑
I'm not joking.
我会把他的眼珠子戳瞎
I will poke his eyeballs out, and...
你怎么能这么说  你看到我发去的视频了
How can you say that? You saw the video I sent.
我没撒谎
I'm not lying.
女士
Madam, Madam,
请冷静
c-calm yourself.
如果一万块太多了  我们可以
If $10,000 is too much, I'm sure we can...
喂  喂
Hello? Hello?
真让人失望
Well, that's disappointing.
她居然不信我
She didn't believe me.
你肯定很调皮
You must be quite the scamp.
我来应付吧
I got it.
又见面了  小姑娘
Hello again, young lady.
有事吗
How can I help you?
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
这下你想谈了啊
So, now you want to talk, huh?
好吧  没事的
Okay. It's all right.
谢谢
Thanks.
塞琳娜啊
Selina is it?
小猫
Cat.
你是迈奇的朋友
You Macky's friend?
嗯  我认识迈奇
Yeah, I know Macky.
那些混蛋差点两次抓到你
Those bastards nearly got you twice, huh?
你生命力挺强啊
You're quite a survivor.
你根本想不到
You have no idea.
如果我有你非常想要的东西
Suppose I had something you really, really wanted.
如果我给了你
If I gave it to you,
你能把我弄出去吗
could you get me out of here?
你有什么
What do you got?
我一直在观察你
I've been watching you.
你是那男孩的朋友
You're a friend of the boy.
你跟其他那些坏警察不一样
You're not like the rest of these crooks.
男孩  布鲁斯吗
The boy? Bruce?
什么叫你一直在观察我
What do you mean, you've been watching me?
那个马里奥・佩珀是个替罪羊吧
That Mario Pepper guy was a patsy, huh?
你为什么那么说
What makes you say that?
你能把我弄出去吗
Could you? Could you get me out?
能做到
It's possible.
我看到杀死韦恩夫妇的真凶了
I saw who really killed the Waynes.
看得很清楚
Saw him clear as day.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com